{
  "Primary": {
    "Problem-Solving": [
      {
        "question": "There are 3 red balls and 2 blue balls in a bag. How many balls are there in total?",
        "choices": [
          "3",
          "4",
          "5",
          "6"
        ],
        "answer": "5"
      },
      {
        "question": "Sarah has 4 cookies and she eats 2. How many cookies does she have left?",
        "choices": [
          "1",
          "2",
          "3",
          "4"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
      },
      {
        "question": "Tom has 5 toy cars and his friend gives him 2 more. How many toy cars does Tom have now?",
        "choices": [
          "2",
          "5",
          "7",
          "10"
        ],
        "answer": "7"
      },
      {
        "question": "Alex has 6 pencils and 3 pens in his backpack. How many writing utensils does he have in total?",
        "choices": [
          "3",
          "6",
          "9",
          "12"
        ],
        "answer": "9"
      },
      {
        "question": "Lily has 8 apples in her basket. She gives 4 apples to her friend. How many apples does Lily have left?",
        "choices": [
          "2",
          "4",
          "6",
          "8"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
      }
    ],
    "Numbers": [
      {
        "question": "What number comes after 7?",
        "choices": [
          "6",
          "7",
          "8",
          "9"
        ],
        "answer": "8"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is bigger: 6 or 8?",
        "choices": [
          "6",
          "8"
        ],
        "answer": "8"
      },
      {
        "question": "What number comes before 15?",
        "choices": [
          "12",
          "13",
          "14",
          "15"
        ],
        "answer": "14"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is smaller: 4 or 9?",
        "choices": [
          "4",
          "9"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
      },
      {
        "question": "What number is one more than 18?",
        "choices": [
          "18",
          "19",
          "20",
          "21"
        ],
        "answer": "19"
      }
    ],
    "Computation": [
      {
        "question": "2 + 3 = ?",
        "choices": [
          "1",
          "5",
          "6",
          "7"
        ],
        "answer": "5"
      },
      {
        "question": "5 - 1 = ?",
        "choices": [
          "4",
          "5",
          "6",
          "7"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
      },
      {
        "question": "2 + 33 = ?",
        "choices": [
          "1",
          "35",
          "6",
          "7"
        ],
        "answer": "35"
      },
      {
        "question": "50 - 1 = ?",
        "choices": [
          "49",
          "5",
          "6",
          "7"
        ],
        "answer": "49"
      },
      {
        "question": "2 + 13 = ?",
        "choices": [
          "1",
          "5",
          "6",
          "15"
        ],
        "answer": "15"
      }
    ],
    "Measurement": [
      {
        "question": "Which is taller: a tree or a flower?",
        "choices": [
          "tree",
          "flower"
        ],
        "answer": "tree"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is heavier: a book or a feather?",
        "choices": [
          "book",
          "feather"
        ],
        "answer": "book"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is more expensive: a cup of coffee or a gallon of gas?",
        "choices": [
          "cup of coffee",
          "gallon of gas"
        ],
        "answer": "gallon of gas"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is faster: a bicycle or a car?",
        "choices": [
          "bicycle",
          "car"
        ],
        "answer": "car"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which has more pages: a magazine or a book?",
        "choices": [
          "magazine",
          "book"
        ],
        "answer": "book"
      }
    ],
    "Geometry": [
      {
        "question": "How many sides does a square have?",
        "choices": [
          "3",
          "4",
          "5",
          "6"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
      },
      {
        "question": "How many corners does a triangle have?",
        "choices": [
          "1",
          "2",
          "3",
          "4"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
      },
      {
        "question": "How many legs does a cat have?",
        "choices": [
          "2",
          "3",
          "4",
          "6"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
      },
      {
        "question": "How many wheels does a bicycle have?",
        "choices": [
          "1",
          "2",
          "3",
          "4"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
      },
      {
        "question": "How many eyes does a human have?",
        "choices": [
          "1",
          "2",
          "3",
          "4"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
      }
    ]
  },
  "Upper Elementary": {
    "Problem-Solving": [
      {
        "question": "You need to find the number that solves the equation 3x−5=7. Which of these numbers is the correct solution?",
        "choices": [
          "3",
          "4",
          "5",
          "6"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
      },
      {
        "question": "You have a number that, when multiplied by 4, gives 36. What is the number?",
        "choices": [
          "1",
          "9",
          "3",
          "4"
        ],
        "answer": "9"
      },
      {
        "question": "You have a number that, when divided by 3, gives 5. What is the number?",
        "choices": [
          "2",
          "5",
          "7",
          "15"
        ],
        "answer": "15"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following fractions is equivalent to 1/2?",
        "choices": [
          "1/3",
          "2/8",
          "3/6",
          "2/6"
          
        ],
        "answer": "3/6"
      },
      {
        "question": "Find the number that, when added to 15, gives 28.",
        "choices": [
          "13",
          "4",
          "10",
          "11"
        ],
        "answer": "13"
      }
    ],
    "Numbers": [
      {
        "question": "Which of the following decimals is the largest?",
        "choices": [
          "0.62",
          "0.56",
          "0.75",
          "0.49"
        ],
        "answer": "0.75"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following fractions is simplified to its lowest terms?",
        "choices": [
          "4/8",
          "3/9",
          "2/5",
          "6/12"
        ],
        "answer": "2/5"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following numbers is an even number?",
        "choices": [
          "12",
          "13",
          "15",
          "17"
        ],
        "answer": "12"
      },
      {
        "question": "In the number 7,825, what is the place value of the digit 8?",
        "choices": [
          "Units",
          "Tens",
          "Hundreds",
          "Thousands"
        ],
        "answer": "Hundreds"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the result of 5.5 - 2.75  ?",
        "choices": [
          "2.75",
          "2.5",
          "2.25",
          "3.5"
        ],
        "answer": "2.75"
      }
    ],
    "Computation": [
      {
        "question": "What is the sum of 456 and 789?",
        "choices": [
          "1145",
          "1235",
          "1245",
          "1255"
        ],
        "answer": "1245"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the result of subtracting 2.75 from 5.80?",
        "choices": [
          "2.05",
          "2.15",
          "3.05",
          "3.15"
        ],
        "answer": "3.05"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the product of 12 and 8?",
        "choices": [
          "80",
          "86",
          "92",
          "96"
        ],
        "answer": "96"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is 14.4 divided by 1.2?",
        "choices": [
          "11",
          "12",
          "13",
          "14"
        ],
        "answer": "12"
      },
      {
        "question": "Using a calculator, what is (25.5×2)(10.2+4.3)?",
        "choices": [
          "30.5",
          "31.2",
          "32.8",
          "35.4"
        ],
        "answer": "31.2"
      }
    ],
    "Measurement": [
      {
        "question": "What is the area of a rectangle with a length of 8 cm and a width of 5 cm?",
        "choices": [
          "13 cm²",
          "30 cm²",
          "40 cm²",
          "48 cm²"
        ],
        "answer": "40 cm²"
      },
      {
        "question": "If one apple weighs 150 grams, what is the total mass of 4 apples?",
        "choices": [
          "450 grams",
          "500 grams",
          "600 grams",
          "750 grams"
        ],
        "answer": "600 grams"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the volume of a box that is 3 meters long, 2 meters wide, and 4 meters high?",
        "choices": [
          "18 cubic meters",
          "20 cubic meters",
          "24 cubic meters",
          "30 cubic meters"
        ],
        "answer": "24 cubic meters"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the circumference of a circle with a radius of 7 cm? (Use π≈3.14)",
        "choices": [
          "21.98 cm",
          "38.48 cm",
          "43.96 cm",
          "44.00 cm"
        ],
        "answer": "43.96 cm"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the perimeter of a square with each side measuring 6 meters?",
        "choices": [
          "18 meters",
          "20 meters",
          "24 meters",
          "30 meters"
        ],
        "answer": "24 meters"
      }
    ],
    "Geometry": [
      {
        "question": "What type of angle is formed when two lines meet to form a right angle?",
        "choices": [
          "Acute angle",
          "Obtuse angle",
          "Right angle",
          "Reflex angle"
        ],
        "answer": " Right angle"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which pair of triangles are similar?",
        "choices": [
          "One triangle has sides 3 cm, 4 cm, and 5 cm, and the other has sides 6 cm, 8 cm, and 10 cm",
          "One triangle has sides 3 cm, 4 cm, and 5 cm, and the other has sides 4 cm, 5 cm, and 6 cm",
          "One triangle has sides 3 cm, 4 cm, and 5 cm, and the other has sides 2 cm, 3 cm, and 4 cm",
          "One triangle has sides 3 cm, 4 cm, and 5 cm, and the other has sides 9 cm, 12 cm, and 15 cm"
        ],
        "answer": "One triangle has sides 3 cm, 4 cm, and 5 cm, and the other has sides 6 cm, 8 cm, and 10 cm"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which shape has rotational symmetry?",
        "choices": [
          "Square",
          "Rectangle",
          "Equilateral triangle",
          "Scalene triangle"
        ],
        "answer": "Square"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which statement about congruent shapes is true?",
        "choices": [
          "They have the same shape but may have different sizes",
          "They have the same size but may have different shapes",
          "They have the same size and shape",
          "They have neither the same size nor the same shape"
        ],
        "answer": "They have the same size and shape"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a triangle, what is the sum of the measures of its interior angles?",
        "choices": [
          "90 degrees",
          "180 degrees",
          "270 degrees",
          "360 degrees"
        ],
        "answer": "180 degrees"
      }
    ]},
    "Middle School": {
      "Problem-Solving": [
        {
          "question": "If 4 friends share 12 candies equally, how many candies does each friend get?",
          "choices": [
            "2 candies",
            "3 candies",
            "4 candies",
            "6 candies"
          ],
          "answer": "3 candies"
        },
        {
          "question": "If a recipe to make 6 cookies requires 1 cup of flour, how much flour is needed to make 12 cookies?",
          "choices": [
            "1/2 cup",
            "1 cup",
            "1 1/2 cups",
            "2 cups"
          ],
          "answer": "2 cups"
        },
        {
          "question": "If 3 apples cost $1.50, how much would 5 apples cost?",
          "choices": [
            "$1.00",
            "$2.00",
            "$2.50",
            "$3.00"
          ],
          "answer": "$2.50"
        },
        {
          "question": "If a square has a side length of 2 inches, how long would the side of a similar square be if it is scaled by a factor of 3?",
          "choices": [
            "3 inches",
            "4 inches",
            "5 inches",
            "6 inches"
          ],
          "answer": "6 inches"
        },
        {
          "question": "If 2 friends take turns playing with a toy for 10 minutes each, how long do they play together in total?",
          "choices": [
            "10 minutes",
            "15 minutes",
            "20 minutes",
            "25 minutes"
          ],
          "answer": "20 minutes"
        }
      ],
      "Numbers": [
        {
          "question": "Which of the following numbers is a rational number?",
          "choices": [
            "0.5",
            "π",
            "√2​",
            "√9"
          ],
          "answer": "0.5"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is 2^3 ?",
          "choices": [
            "6",
            "8",
            "12",
            "16"
          ],
          "answer": "8"
        },
        {
          "question": "Write 5,000 in scientific notation?",
          "choices": [
            "5 × 10",
            "5 × 10³",
            " 5 × 10⁴",
            "5 × 10⁵"
          ],
          "answer": "5 × 10⁴"
        },
        {
          "question": "If a basket has 3 red apples and 5 green apples, what is the ratio of red apples to green apples?",
          "choices": [
            "3:5",
            "5:3",
            "3:8",
            "8:3"
          ],
          "answer": "3:5"
        },
        {
          "question": "If you have 20 marbles and 4 of them are blue, what percentage of the marbles are blue?",
          "choices": [
            "8%",
            "19%",
            "20%",
            "21%"
          ],
          "answer": "20%"
        }
      ],
      "Computation": [
        {
          "question": "What is 2.5 + 3.75 = ?",
          "choices": [
            "5.25",
            "6.25",
            "6.5",
            "7.25"
          ],
          "answer": "6.5"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is 5/8 - 1/4 = ?",
          "choices": [
            "1/8",
            "1/4",
            "3/8",
            "3/4"
          ],
          "answer": "3/8"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is 3.1/2 + 2.2/3 = ?",
          "choices": [
            "6.1/6",
            "7.1/3",
            "8.1/6",
            "9.1/3"
          ],
          "answer": "7.1/3"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is 3/4 ÷ 1/2  = ?",
          "choices": [
            "1/8",
            "1/2",
            "3/2",
            "4/3"
          ],
          "answer": "3/2"
        },
        {
          "question": "Estimate the product of 2.5×3.8",
          "choices": [
            "10",
            "51",
            "6",
            "15"
          ],
          "answer": "15"
        }
      ],
      "Measurement": [
        {
          "question": "If Sarah runs 3 miles in 30 minutes, what is her average speed in miles per hour?",
          "choices": [
            "3 mph",
            "4 mph",
            "5 mph",
            "6 mph"
          ],
          "answer": "4 mph"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which unit would you use to measure the weight of a textbook?",
          "choices": [
            "Kilogram (kg)",
            "Meter (m)",
            "Liter (L)",
            "Second (s)"
          ],
          "answer": "Kilogram (kg)"
        },
        {
          "question": "If the scale of a map is 1 inch represents 5 miles, how many inches on the map would represent a distance of 25 miles?",
          "choices": [
            "2 inches",
            "3 inches",
            "4 inches",
            "5 inches"
          ],
          "answer": "4 inches"
        },
        {
          "question": "If a tree casts a shadow of 10 feet at the same time a 3-foot-tall fence post casts a shadow of 2 feet, how tall is the tree?",
          "choices": [
            "12 feet",
            "15 feet",
            "20 feet",
            "25 feet"
          ],
          "answer": "20 feet"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the surface area of a cube with a side length of 4 inches?",
          "choices": [
            "16 square inches",
            "24 square inches",
            "32 square inches",
            "48 square inches"
          ],
          "answer": "48 square inches"
        }
      ],
      "Geometry": [
        {
          "question": "What is the slope of a line that passes through points (2, 3) and (4, 7)?",
          "choices": [
            "1/2",
            "2/3",
            "3/2",
            "2"
          ],
          "answer": "2"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following shapes has 6 faces, 8 vertices, and 12 edges?",
          "choices": [
            "Sphere",
            "Cube",
            "Cylinder",
            "Cone"
          ],
          "answer": "Cube"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which pair of lines are parallel?",
          "choices": [
            "y=2x+3 and y=2x−1",
            "y=3x+1 and y=-1/3x+2",
            "y=-2x+4 and y=2x+4",
            "y=1/2x+3 and y=2x+3"
          ],
          "answer": "y=2x+3 and y=2x−1"
        },
        {
          "question": "In a right triangle, if one leg measures 5 units and the other leg measures 12 units, what is the length of the hypotenuse?",
          "choices": [
            "13 units",
            "15 units",
            "17 units",
            "20 units"
          ],
          "answer": "13 units"
        },
        {
          "question": "If a car travels 50 miles in 2 hours, what is its average speed in miles per hour?",
          "choices": [
            "20 mph",
            "25 mph",
            "30 mph",
            "35 mph"
          ],
          "answer": "25 mph"
        }
      ]
    },
    "High School": {
      "Problem-Solving": [
        {
          "question": "Which proof technique involves assuming the opposite of what needs to be proven and then arriving at a contradiction?",
          "choices": [
            "Direct proof",
            "Proof by contradiction",
            "Inductive proof",
            "Proof by exhaustion"
          ],
          "answer": "Proof by contradiction"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which algorithm sorts a list by repeatedly stepping through the list, comparing adjacent elements, and swapping them if they are in the wrong order?",
          "choices": [
            "Merge sort",
            "Insertion sort",
            "Quick sort",
            "Selection sort"
          ],
          "answer": "Insertion sort"
        },
        {
          "question": "In a proof by mathematical induction, what are the two main steps involved?",
          "choices": [
            "Base case and hypothesis",
            "Hypothesis and conclusion",
            "Inductive step and conclusion",
            "Base case and inductive step"
          ],
          "answer": "Base case and inductive step"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which algorithm typically has the best average and worst-case time complexity for sorting a list of n elements?",
          "choices": [
            "Bubble sort",
            "Quick sort",
            "Selection sort",
            "Insertion sort"
          ],
          "answer": "Quick sort"
        },
        {
          "question": "What type of proof uses logical arguments based on geometric principles to establish the truth of a statement about shapes or figures?",
          "choices": [
            "Algebraic proof",
            "Inductive proof",
            "Deductive proof",
            "Geometric proof"
          ],
          "answer": "Geometric proof"
        }
      ],
      "Numbers": [
        {
          "question": "Which of the following numbers is a real number?",
          "choices": [
            "√-1",
            "3/0",
            "π",
            "0.3"
          ],
          "answer": "π"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which type of number is √25?",
          "choices": [
            "Irrational",
            "Rational",
            "Integer",
            "Natural"
          ],
          "answer": "Rational"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which inequality represents x is greater than or equal to 3?",
          "choices": [
            "x > 3",
            "x < 3",
            "x ≥ 3",
            "x ≤ 3"
          ],
          "answer": "x ≥ 3"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the solution set of the inequality 2x+5<15?",
          "choices": [
            "x > 5",
            "x < 5",
            "x ≥ 5",
            "x ≤ 5"
          ],
          "answer": "x ≤ 5"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which inequality represents the absolute value of x is less than 4 ?",
          "choices": [
            "∣x∣ < 4",
            "∣x∣ > 4",
            "∣x∣ ≤ 4",
            "∣x∣ ≥ 4"
          ],
          "answer": "∣x∣ < 4"
        }
      ],
      "Computation": [
        {
          "question": "3x^2+4x−2x^2+5x?",
          "choices": [
            "x^2+9x",
            "x^2+2x",
            "5x^2+9x",
            "x^2+7x"
          ],
          "answer": "x^2+7x"
        },
        {
          "question": "2y^2−3y−(y^2−2y)",
          "choices": [
            "y^2−y",
            "y^2−5y",
            "y^2+y",
            "y^2−2y"
          ],
          "answer": "y^2−y"
        },
        {
          "question": " √25 + √9",
          "choices": [
            "2√7",
            "8",
            "10",
            "7"
          ],
          "answer": "8"
        },
        {
          "question": "(4x^2−3x+7)−(2x^2+5x−3)",
          "choices": [
            "2x^2−8x+10",
            "2x^2+8x+10",
            "2x^2−8x+4",
            "2x^2+8x+4"
          ],
          "answer": "2x^2−8x+10"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is (2^3×3^2)÷(2^2×3^1)?",
          "choices": [
            "2",
            "5",
            "6",
            "17"
          ],
          "answer": "6"
        }
      ],
      "Measurement": [
        {
          "question": "Which of the following best describes velocity?",
          "choices": [
            "The speed of an object",
            "The distance traveled by an object",
            "The rate of change of position of an object with respect to time",
            "The force applied to an object"
          ],
          "answer": "The rate of change of position of an object with respect to time"
        },
        {
          "question": "Acceleration is defined as:",
          "choices": [
            "The change in speed of an object",
            "The direction of motion of an object",
            "The force acting on an object",
            "The rate of change of velocity of an object"
          ],
          "answer": "The rate of change of velocity of an object"
        },
        {
          "question": "Precision in measurements refers to:",
          "choices": [
            "How close a measured value is to the true value",
            "How consistent repeated measurements are",
            "How small the smallest measurable division is",
            "How sensitive the measuring instrument is"
          ],
          "answer": "How consistent repeated measurements are"
        },
        {
          "question": "Tolerance in measurements refers to:",
          "choices": [
            "The degree of consistency between measurements",
            "The maximum acceptable deviation from a desired measurement",
            "The smallest possible measurement that can be made",
            "The accuracy of the measuring instrument"
          ],
          "answer": "The maximum acceptable deviation from a desired measurement"
        },
        {
          "question": "If a car travels 120 miles in 2 hours, what is its average velocity?",
          "choices": [
            "60 mph",
            "70 mph",
            "80 mph",
            "90 mph"
          ],
          "answer": "60 mph"
        }
      ],
      "Geometry": [
        {
          "question": "In a right triangle, if the lengths of the legs are 6 units and 8 units, what is the length of the hypotenuse?",
          "choices": [
            "10 units",
            "12 units",
            "14 units",
            "15 units"
          ],
          "answer": "10 units"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the magnitude of the vector v=⟨3,4⟩?",
          "choices": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "5"
          ],
          "answer": "5"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the resultant vector of a=⟨2,3⟩ and b=⟨4,1⟩?",
          "choices": [
            "⟨6,4⟩",
            "⟨6,3⟩",
            "⟨2,4⟩",
            "⟨2,1⟩"
          ],
          "answer": "⟨6,4⟩"
        },
        {
          "question": "If a point (x,y) is translated by 3 units to the right and 2 units down, what are the coordinates of the new point?",
          "choices": [
            "(x+3,y−2)",
            "(x−3,y+2)",
            "(x+2,y−3)",
            "(x−2,y+3)"
          ],
          "answer": "(x+3,y−2)"
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the coordinates of the point (1,2) after a 90-degree rotation counterclockwise around the origin?",
          "choices": [
            "(−1,2)",
            "(2,−1)",
            "(−2,1)",
            "(1,−2)"
          ],
          "answer": "(−2,1)"
        }
      ]
    }
}
